

ZAIN TANVEER

zat938@gmail.com

A House# 202, Jade Block, Park View Villas, Thokar Nia: Lahore, Pakistan

+92 320 4419651

https://www.linkedin.com/in/zain-tanveer-571bb717a/

Summary

- Adept in Front-End, Mobile/Hybrid and Desktop Development.
- Solid coding skills in Python, JS, Java & experience of RESTful API's via Json.
- Self-experience and variety of Projects.
- Willingness to work with unfamiliar bleeding edge technologies.
- Well versed with algorithm, OOP, DSA, Design Patterns, Programming practice &SDLC

Technical Skill

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JS ES6), Python, Java, C++, C#, SQL.

Technologies: JSX, Ajax, JSON, PythonSocket, Firebase (BAAS)

UI Tools: PyQt, Tkinter, JavaFX, Android Framework UI, WPF.

Protocols: TCP/IP, UDP, SSL, HTTP/HTTPS

Platforms: Windows, Android, Linux

Frameworks: ReactNative, ASP.NET MVC

Libraries: ReactJS, Picasso, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, Scikit-learn.

API Exp: Google-maps, Authentication, Realtime-Database, Notifications.

Data Visualization: Matplotlib, Seaborn

Misc.: Version Control GIT, Adobe Suite, CoralDraw.

Education

BS in Software Engineering

Oct 2015 – July 2019

CGPA: 3.0

PUCIT – Punjab University College of Information and Technology.

Experience

Python Developer

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Freelancer

- Created Desktop Application for clients and have handled Data Analysis with 100% positive feedback.
- Tutored various other projects and Software.
- Administered the SDLC and have Ensured results

Intern Software Engineer

Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

Exponento (Pvt)

- Focused on user experience, and design responsive web based friendly userinterface.
- Worked in accordance with agile, attending daily Scrums and working in a team.

Awards and Certificates

Stood 20th out of 32 teams in Coding Knights event.

SoloLearn: Python, Javascript, C++, HTML & Udemy Data Structure CodeCamp.

Awarded PEEF Scholarship, Laptop.

Projects

BloodBud - FYP - Android/ Firebase

 Finding Potential Blood Donors now easier. Our project is Spearhead that shines when time is of critical importance. Orchestrated team and assessed the SDLC together

Backk - Android

 Let's user play their favorite YouTube platform as a Music Player even after a user navigate back or turn screen off. Single handedly designed the GUI and administered the Development.

Rock-Paper-Scissor - Web Game

 Single handedly combined HTML with CSS to create an elegant design which is backed up by Javascript to dynamically handle events.

Library Management Sys - Full Stack Web App

- Has Library Catalogue. Manager can lent book to user and the system also has checkout/check-in features.
- Implemented web services using .NET and SQL-Server for Business Logic.

Word Predictor- ML/Neural Networks

- Initial Dataset provided by Kaggle, built a model using RNN, 1-hot encoding vectors and machine learning libraries.
- Team-project, we established knowledge in Text Normalization, then we trained the model to predict next 3 words. Led a discussion and determined each member's role.

Desktop Messenger – Python PyQt

Social Messenger developed using python libraries and socket/ ports & channels.
 Single handedly designed the GUI using PyQt and established my knowledge in computer networking

Other Projects:

- Web Crawler with Python Personal Project
- Stockvu Python Freelancer Project

Interests

Data Science R & D Internet of Things

Game Dev. AR/ VR